TAREMWA TADEO Kampala, Uganda (+256) 771414233 / 702467771

taremwatadeo@outlook.com

Profile

I am a hands-on highly competent IT Specialist with 4 years' training in software engineering practices from Makerere University. I possess knowledge and skills in Requirements engineering, object oriented analysis and design, systems analysis and design and Business process management and I also possess basic programming knowledge in java and python and Linux system administration. I am currently pursuing professional certifications in Oracle and SQL.

Objective

I am seeking a career in design and management of Software Systems, database administration and maintenance, systems administration and management of Computer networks in a challenging environment that utilizes team work, has effort for researching, learning and developing high-tech solutions for clients that will leverage an organisation's opportunity for advancement.

Education

Makerere University, Kampala (2013 to 2017)

Bachelors of Science in Software Engineering

Crested Secondary School, Makindye (2011-2012)

Uganda Advanced Certificate of Education

City High School, Kampala (2007-2010)

Uganda Certificate of Education

Working Experience

IT Consultant Shore Limited Uganda (March 2017)

Shore limited is a research based company in uganda dealing in data collection and data analysis for big projects. I offered consultancy to the company on joining the oracle partner network (OPN) from an IT perspective which was successful and now the company is an oracle partner on the silver partnership level.

Release Manager OpenMRS (June 2016 – November 2016)

OpenMRS is an open source Medical Record System used to support the delivery of healthcare in developing countries.

Every year two releases are made for the OpenMRS system and I was selected as the Release Manager of OpenMRS Reference Application 2.5, my roles being;

- To attend and organize project management meetings
- Create the release management process
- Create tickets on JIRA for bugs that must be fixed in the release
- communicate the modules that shall be contained in the release and encourage module owners to upgrade them for compatibility.
- Setting deadlines and follow up on the module developers
- Updating the CIEL dictionary and exporting concepts
- Updating the OpenMRS Mysql instance
- Planning and spearheading the User Acceptance Testing(UAT) process
- Deploying the software on the User Acceptance Testing server
- Releasing all the modules that are to be included in the release
- Realising the distribution from CI (Continuous Integration)
- Writing the documentation and release notes for the release
- Releasing the distribution in JIRA
- Uploading the release on sourceforge to be available to users
- Deploying the release on the Demo server.
- updating the blog about the new release
- Announcing the release to the community and implementers

Trainer Africa Code Week (October 2016)

I participated in the training of over 200 pupils and students in programing skills using the scratch software.

The pupils and students from the selected schools were trained from makerere university college of computing and information sciences (COCIS) and college of engineering, design, art and technology (CEDAT) Labs.

The trainees were trained to develop simple to complex games using scratch software and they were also taught to write the basic programming syntax for beginners.

Intern Ministry of Finance ,Planning and Economic Development, Kampala (June 2016 - August,2016)

I was appointed as an intern at the ministry of finance for a period of three months, during this time i managed to achieve the following;

- microsoft server administration
- Adding new employers to the workstation network
- software installations for employees
- Training the employees on using microsoft office (excel)
- routers and switches troubleshooting
- Cable termination with RJ45 connectors

Achievements

- Team Leader (2014-2017) OpenMRS Student Contributors Uganda Cohort
- College President (2016-2017) College of computing and Information
 Sciences Makerere University
- Minister of Information and Computing Technology (2016-2017)
 Makerere University Private Students Association.
- Western Region Coordinator(2015-2017) Knowledge for Life initiative uganda
- Chairman (2014-2016)Makerere University Ndorwa West Students Association
- Publicity (2014-2015) Uganda Redcross Society ,Makerere Chapter
- Class Representative (2013-2014) Software Engineering Class
- Mess Minister (2011-2012) Crested Secondary School Makindye.

Technical Skills

- Database administration using tools such as SQL developer
- Microsoft office package proficient.
- Microsoft Server administration and management
- Linux System Administration
- Linux Server administration and maintenance
- Software development using object oriented approach

- Computer networks troubleshooting
- Report Writing
- Data collection and analysis using statistical tools for example spss
- Requirements engineering
- Basic Digital skills

Professional Skills

- Excellent interpersonal skills.
- Good communication and Presentation skills.
- Good entrepreneurial skills, including pitching business ideas and determining viability of ventures.
- Analytical and self-driven.
- Good leadership skills.
- Planning & Organization skills, including putting business plans on paper, and project scheduling
- Quick learning skills

Personal Data

Gender: Male

Date of Birth: 13th August 1993

Languages Spoken: Luganda, Rukiga-Runyankore and English

Marital Status: Single

Referees

Assoc.Prof Dr Burke Mamlin

Indiana University School of Medicine

Co-Founder and Project Lead OpenMRS,Inc.

Research Scientist, Regenstrief Institute, Inc.

bmamlin@regenstrief.org

Assoc.Prof Gilbert Maiga

Dean School of Computing and Informatics Technology

Makerere University

gilmaiga@gmail.com

+256 772316918

Professor Constant Okello-Obura

Principal College of Computing and Information sciences

Makerere University

obura2007@gmail.com

+256 772590827